时间
Time.
空间
Space.
现实
Reality.
它们不仅仅是线性的
It's more than a linear path.
而是一个拥有无限可能的棱镜
It's a prism of endless possibility,
一个选择便能开辟出无数个现实
where a single choice can branch out into infinite realities,
创造出与你所知不同的平行世界
creating alternate worlds from the ones you know.
我是观察者
I am the Watcher.
我将带领你们穿越这些新现实
I am your guide through these vast new realities.
跟随我来  并思考这个问题
Follow me and ponder the question...
“假如呢?”
"What if?"
在你眼中的银河系是一千亿个光点
The galaxy, to your eyes, a hundred billion points of light.
但是在你看到光的地方 我看到了一个充满故事的世界
But where you see light, I see worlds and the countless stories that fill them.
但在一个有无限可能的多元宇宙中
But in a Multiverse of infinite possibility,
你的命运是由你的本性决定的还是由你的世界的本性决定的?
is your destiny determined by your nature or by the nature of your world?
放下它!就现在!
Drop it! Drop it now!
你是谁?
Who are you?
自报家门
Identify yourself.
谁,我吗?我只是一艘普通的瘾君子
Who, me? I am just an ordinary junker.
但有一个名字你可能知道
But there is one name you may know me by.
哦,我的星爵!
Oh, my. Star-Lord!
我是你的超级粉丝你在这里做什么?
I'm a huge fan of your work. What are you doing here?
这可不是我所期待的反应
That was not the reaction I was expecting.
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿停!表现出一些尊重
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Stop! Show some respect.
这是星爵，传奇的亡命之徒
This is the Star-Lord, legendary outlaw.
劫富济贫
Steals from the powerful and gives to the powerless.
我们应该鞠躬吗?我觉得我们该鞠躬了
Should we be bowing? I feel like we should be bowing.
我是说，除非我们应该跪着
I mean, unless we should be kneeling.
都不应该-拜托
-Neither is necessary. -Please.
-你可是星爵-这不是官方头衔
-You are a lord. -It is not an official title.
-我也不喜欢这样
-Nor is it one I am comfortable with.
你当然会很谦虚 星爵
Of course you would be humble. Classic Star-Lord.
我真希望我不用从你这里夺走它
I almost wish I didn't have to take that from you.
这么强大的东西放在我手里肯定更好
Surely something this powerful is better off in my hands.
只是我的老板，罗南，非常非常紧张
It's just that my boss, Ronan, super, super intense.
但我可能会被说服换一份工作
But I could be convinced to make a career change.
谢谢你的关心，但我们人手都满了
Appreciate the interest, but we're all staffed up.
哦,懂了懂了 但至少我得和你打一架
Oh, totally. Totally get it. But at least now I get to spar with you.
如果你真想这样的话
I guess if that's really what you want.
这将是我一生的荣幸
Oh, it shall be the honor of my life.
-哦我不该用枪吗? -发问吧
-Oh. Uh, should I not use the gun? -Go ahead.
-真的?-请
-Really? -Please.
不，这不是问题
No, it's not a problem.
-我会处理掉的——没问题
-I'll get rid of it. -It's okay.
你确定吗?-来吧，用枪
-You sure? -Go ahead, use the gun.
你真是太慷慨了
That is so generous of you.
准备好了吗?-噢,是的
-Ready? - Oh, yes.
哦
Oh.
星爵，您没有让我失望如此敏捷，如此敏捷
You do not disappoint, my lord. So nimble, so spry.
我就在这里 来打我
I'm right here. Hit me.
-哦大人!我不是故意的-这就是我们来的目的
-Oh. My Lord! I didn't mean to... -That is what we're here for.
再做一次但这次，要快一点
Do it again. But this time, faster.
使点劲-真的?
-Harder. -Really?
我几乎就没躲 打我
I barely moved. Hit me.
星爵
Classic Star-Lord.
现在我感觉糟透了
Now I almost feel bad.
我雇过更糟的
Well, I have hired worse.
站住,劫掠者 我们把你包围了
Freeze, Ravager. We have you outnumbered.
看起来是这样，但掠夺者从来不独行
It would appear, but a Ravager never flies solo.
我说"劫掠者从不独行"
I said, "A Ravager never flies solo."
这是什么口头禅吗?
Uh, is that some kind of catchphrase?
你让我担心了一会儿
You had me worried for a second.
这睡美人是谁? -新员工 他也在追求这个
-Who's the Sleeping Beauty? -A new recruit. He was after this as well.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
热信号爆表了
Thermal signature's off the charts.
如果我们想找点乐子，
You know, if we wanted to have some real fun,
我们应该像以前一样
we'd make like the old days
把这坏东西卖给出价最高的人
and sell this bad boy to the highest bidder.
如果我们像以前那样做，你就只剩一半牙齿了
If we made like the old days, you'd only have half of your teeth.
再说了，你难道不想用它来启动
Besides, wouldn't you rather use it to jump-start
克瑞洛人垂死的星球，拯救他们的系统免于灭绝?
the Krylorians' dying star, save their system from extinction?
你和我一样清楚，任何宝藏都不值钱
You know as well as I, no treasure is worth as much
就像用它能做的好事一样
as the good that can be done with it.
啊这是我的孩子
Ah. That's my boy.
虽然我们的英雄旅程 可能在天上的星星
Though our hero's destiny might lie in the stars above,
但旅程的开始 更应脚踏实地
the beginning of his journey was much more down-to-earth.
我厌倦了生活在泡泡里
I am tired of living in a bubble.
外面有一个完整的世界，爸爸
There's an entire world out there, Baba.
是的，战争，暴力，仇恨
Yes, one of war, violence, hatred.
那个世界给瓦坎达什么都没有
That world has nothing to offer Wakanda.
肯定还有更多但我们必须勇敢地去寻找它
There must be more. But we must be brave enough to search for it.
我明白，我的儿子
I do understand, my son.
虽然你的血管里流着国王的血，
Though the blood of a king runs through your veins,
它是由探险家的心脏泵送的
it is pumped by the heart of an explorer.
但作为一个冒险探索更广阔世界的人，
But as someone who has ventured out into the greater world,
我向你保证，
let me assure you,
你会发现那里只有毁灭和痛苦
all you will find there is destruction and pain.
那些人不了解我们的生活方式
Those people do not understand our way of life.
你所谓的命运 只是一个等式，
What you call destiny is just an equation,
-变量的乘积
-a product of variables.
对的地点 对的时间 或者在某些情况下，
Right place, right time, or in some instances,
在错误的时间错误的地点
the wrong place at the wrong time.
正如命运所愿， 在那一刻，
As fate would have it, at that very moment,
一艘毁灭者宇宙飞船抵达地球 绑架天界的生物，自我
a Ravager spacecraft was arriving on Earth to abduct the spawn of the Celestial, Ego.
酷
Cool.
但是在这个宇宙中，
But in this universe,
勇度把任务外包给他的下属
Yondu outsourced the assignment to his subordinates.
你们这群白痴抓错人了
You morons grabbed the wrong kid.
嗯别急，队长
Uh-uh. Not so fast, Captain.
两个看洞，两个听洞，一个吃洞
Two see holes, two hear holes, one eat hole.
一切正常
Everything checks out.
你们觉得这真像彼得·奎尔吗?
Does this really look like Peter Quill to y'all?
确定我不知道在我看来，所有的人都是一样的
Sure. I don't know. All humans look alike to me.
他被带走的地方的宇宙读数几乎把我们的表盘弄坏了
The cosmic readings where he was took nearly broke our dial.
如果那颗行星上有任何东西不是来自那颗行星，那它就在那里
If there was anything not from that planet on that planet, it's there.
我的家建在一块古老的振金陨石上
Well, my home is built on an ancient Vibranium meteorite.
孩子，你看起来一点都不害怕
You sure don't seem too freaked out about all this, kid.
你一个人在外面干什么?
What you doing out there all by yourself anyway?
探索世界听上去很有趣
-Exploring the world. -Sounds fun.
但为什么只停留在同一个世界呢?
But why stop at one world, huh?
我们什么时候能全部给你看?
When we can show you all of them?
掠夺者!-掠夺者!
-Ravagers! -: Ravagers!
星爵，如果你要选一个最喜欢的…
Star-Lord, if you had to pick a favorite...
真的，我说不上来
Really, I could not say.
我知道，我知道，这么多抢劫，拯救了这么多星球
I know, I know, so many heists, so many planets saved.
不过，你必须有一个
Still, you must have one.
你怎么能只选一个呢?
How could you choose just one?
哦!那中央银行塔纳克斯四世的劫案呢?
Oh! What about the Central Bank heist of Tarnax IV?
伤害斯库尔也无妨，对吧?
Never hurts to hurt a Skrull, right?
那份工作为克莱格林的牙齿买单
That job paid for Kraglin's teeth.
那你武装安卡拉抵抗军的时候呢?
How about when you armed the Ankaran resistance?
哦,男人差点就逃出来了
Oh, man. Barely made it out of that one.
你到底是怎么阻止灭霸，那个疯狂的泰坦，
How exactly did you stop Thanos, the Mad Titan,
来毁灭半个宇宙?哦,不
from decimating half of the universe? Oh, no.
我够大了，能承认自己的错误
I'm a big enough man to admit when I'm wrong.
特查拉告诉了我不止一条路
T'Challa here showed me there was more than one way
重新分配宇宙的资源
to reallocate the universe's resources.
有时候最好的武器就是有力的辩论
Sometimes the best weapon in your arsenal is just a good argument.
是,是,指挥官
Aye, aye, Commander.
虽然我仍然认为我的计划并非一无是处
Although I still assert my plan was not without its merits.
-行去-请
-Here we go. -Please.
我很确定这只是种族灭绝，大个子
Pretty sure it's still just genocide, big guy.
我很确定这是有效的
And I'm pretty sure it's efficient.
你的钱在这里没用
Your money is no good here.
-请-不,我是认真的我们只收现金
-Please. -No, seriously. We only take cash.
哦,我很抱歉我,嗯…我有现金
Oh, I'm sorry. I, uh... I have cash.
等待你是 星爵
Wait. You are the Star-Lord.
你从克里人的入侵中拯救了我的家园
You saved my home world from a Kree invasion.
-这是一天的工作-不，花了好几天
-All in a day's work. -No, it took several days.
6、其实让我们拍张照片发给我的妻子和女儿
Six, in fact. Let us take a picture to send to my wife and daughter.
我宁愿——
I would prefer--
哦，我们应该再拍一张你看起来糟透了我看起来很好
Oh, we should take another one. You look terrible. I look great.
-我肯定没事的-不,我坚持
-I'm sure it's fine. -No, I insist.
-你的照片真难看我不知道
-It is a truly awful picture of you. -WOMAN: I don't know.
从我的角度看，他挺不错的
He looks pretty good from where I'm standing.
星云
Nebula.
嘿,恰恰舞
Hey, Cha-Cha.
你得到了很有价值的战利品
Pretty valuable loot you got here.
那个大家伙知道你有这个吗?
The big guy know you have this?
你是说你父亲?
You mean your father?
他很幸运我叫他大家伙
He's lucky I call him the big guy.
你知道，他现在在做园艺
You know, he gardens now.
你应该和他谈谈他真的变了
You should talk to him. He really has changed.
过去没有
The past doesn't.
你还把过去挂在脖子上
You still wear your past around your neck.
你想过回去吗?
You ever think of going back?
没什么可回去的
Not much to go back to.
我小的时候，勇度想把我送回瓦坎达……
When I was young, Yondu attempted to return me to Wakanda...
但它已经被摧毁了
but it had been destroyed.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
只是又一场毫无意义的战争
Just another senseless war.
爸爸警告说这是所有人类知道的事实证明他是对的
Baba warned that was all humans know. Turns out he was right.
你失去了自己的家，现在又救了其他人的家
You lost your home, and now you save everyone else's.
这就是这首曲子的名字，对吧?
That's the name of this tune, huh?
差不多吧
Something like that.
好吧，那我有份工作给你
Well, then, do I have a job for you.
他们被称为创世纪的余烬
They're called the Embers of Genesis.
来自古老超新星的富含营养的宇宙尘埃
Nutrient-rich cosmic dust from an ancient supernova
有能力改变整个生态系统
with the power to terraform entire ecosystems.
用一盎司，你可以在几分钟内治愈一个濒临死亡的星球
With one ounce, you can heal a dying planet in minutes.
加上我们所说的载荷…
And with a payload the size we're talking...
我们可以养活世界上几十亿人，
We could feed billions of people on millions of worlds,
消除整个银河系的饥饿
and eradicate hunger across the galaxy.
别告诉这里的种族灭绝船长你会扫了他的兴的
Don't tell Captain Genocide over here. You might spoil his fun.
新来的挺有趣的
New guy's pretty funny.
-我以为你是一个人干的，女儿等待,等待,等待
-I thought you work alone, daughter. -Wait, wait, wait.
你是说她是你的孩子?
You mean she's your offspring?
收养的 说来话长
- Adopted. - It's a long story.
我一直想让他们去做心理咨询
I've been trying to get them into counseling.
-那目标是谁?-Taneleer Tivan，也被称为…
-So who's the mark? -Taneleer Tivan, also known as...
收藏家?
The Collector?
是银河系地下世界里最残忍的头目吗?
As in the most ruthless kingpin in the intergalactic underworld?
-等等，我以为是你  -是
-Wait, I thought that was you. -It was.
但当我改邪归正时
But when I went straight,
蒂凡看到了一个缺口，就填补了能量真空
Tivan saw an opening and filled the power vacuum.
我们都同意收藏家很危险
We can all agree the Collector is dangerous.
顺便告诉你，收藏家不提供牙科服务
FYI, the Collector does not offer dental.
这是自杀，特查拉就算是我也无法突破他的防线
This is suicide, T'Challa. Not even I can get through his defenses.
你挖?这个疯子不会杀了你的
You dig? This maniac won't do you the kindness of killing you.
他会为一个科学项目解剖你，
He'll dissect you for a science project,
把剩下的裱起来，挂在墙上
frame whatever's left and hang you up on the wall.
那我该把你记为犹豫不决吗?
So should I mark you down as undecided?
只要收藏者参与其中，我们就不会
So long as the Collector's involved, we are not.
你也许是这艘船的灵魂，但我仍然是船长
You may be the soul of this ship, but I am still the captain.
我们是掠夺者我们不会在战斗中退缩
We are Ravagers. We do not back down from a fight.
不,不我们从富人那里偷东西给穷人，
No, no. We steal from the rich and give to the poor,
就像你那个地球英雄一样，对吧?
just like that earthling folk hero of yours, right?
罗宾·利奇罗宾胡德
-Robin Leach. -Robin Hood.
无论什么这是我们的球拍
Whatever. That's our racket.
我们一直在偷口袋里的硬币
We've been picking pockets for loose coins.
如果我们真的想改变银河系，完成我们想做的一切，
If we truly want to change the galaxy, accomplish all we set out to do,
那我们该抢银行了
then it's time we robbed the bank.
哦,天哪我从来都不善于拒绝你，孩子
Oh, jeez. Never have been any good at saying no to you, kid.
这位收藏家对珍奇的动植物有着著名的癖好
The Collector's got a famous kink for exotic flora and fauna.
余烬会和他的其他战利品一起被安置在这里
The Embers will be housed with the rest of his conquests, here.
一个博物馆兼作他的行动基地
A museum that doubles as his base of operations.
一个远古天神的头颅上刻着一个采矿殖民地
A mining colony in a severed head of an ancient celestial being.
他让黑色骑士团做保安
He's got the Black Order doing security.
相信我，他们是坏消息你打算怎么从他们身边溜过去?
Take it from me, they're bad news. How do you plan on sneaking past them?
我不喜欢我要像个淑女一样去敲他们的前门
I don't. I'm gonna knock on their front door like a lady.
我的夫人星云 Udonta船长
My Lady Nebula. Captain Udonta.
我是来找我主人的
I'm here to fetch you for my master.
Yondu和我将以卖家的身份出现
Yondu and I will pose as sellers
想卸下你在莫拉格取回的球。
looking to unload that orb you recovered on Morag.
但实际上，里面是特查拉
But really, it'll be T'Challa inside.
我们的安全主管，Proxima Midnight
Our head of security, Proxima Midnight.
看来博物馆要办个展览了
Looks like they got an exhibit running the museum.
持有它安全扫描
Hold it. Security scan.
这就是你分散注意力的时候
And that is when you cause the distraction.
停止我以为我们是假装的
Stop. I thought we were faking it.
你再叫我种族灭绝船长吧，新人
Yeah, well, try calling me Captain Genocide again, new guy.
队长种族灭绝…
Captain Genocide...
掠夺者将开始一场骚乱， 引起黑色秩序的注意
The Ravagers will start a riot, drawing the attention of the Black Order.
我们有麻烦了
We have a situation.
所有单位到我们的位置报到
All units report to our position.
现在，勇度和星云 可以分散收集器的注意力，
Now, Yondu and Nebula are free to distract the Collector,
以便我可以搜索余烬
so that I can search for the Embers.
很神奇的
Amazing.
我没有笔记一个完美的计划
I have no notes. A perfect plan.
会出什么问题呢?
What could possibly go wrong?
我向你介绍，塔涅勒·蒂凡，收藏家
I present to you, Taneleer Tivan, the Collector.
哦，我最亲爱的星云
Oh, my dearest Nebula.
你不觉得…
Aren't you a sight for sore...
的眼睛请原谅，我情不自禁
Eye. Forgive me, I couldn't help myself.
嘿,你,creep-show如果你不介意的话，
Hey, you, creep-show. If it's all the same to you,
我想马上就开始做
I'd just as soon get on with it.
所有的业务吗?
All business?
我已经长大了，还记得劫掠者曾经是多么有趣
And to think I'm old enough to remember when the Ravagers used to be fun.
我能说什么呢?我们走直了，我得到了回报
What can I say? We went straight and I got square.
如果你们聊够了，我把你们要的东西带来了
Hey, if you boys are done gossiping, I brought what you asked.
啊
Ugh.
藏品比我预想的要多很多
The collection is much bigger than I anticipated.
所有这些痛苦，为了什么?
All this suffering, and for what?
我猜，他是在弥补什么大事
My guess, he's compensating for something big.
或者很小，如果你明白我的意思
Or small, if you catch my drift.
作为一只鸭子，你口齿伶俐
You are quite articulate for a duck.
先生，你的想法太狭隘了
That, sir, is very close-minded.
你知道，我…我在找一样东西
You know, I, um... I'm looking for something.
创世纪的余烬你知道在哪能找到他们吗?
The Embers of Genesis. Do you know where I can find them?
宇宙植物，大厅那头
Cosmic flora, down the hall.
看冰霜巨人的路易，看克朗人的拉尔夫
Take a Louie at the Frost Giants, a hard Ralph at the Kronans.
你会看到精灵文学的标志忽略它，完全打盹
You'll see a sign for Elvish literature. Ignore that, total snooze.
螺杆
-Screw it.
带我参观一下
Give me the tour.
你知道人们常说"当你运气不好时，
You know what they say, "When you're out of luck,
“总是去鸭子”
"always go duck."
-我很确定没人这么说哦，他们是这么说的
-I'm pretty sure no one says that. -HOWARD: Oh, they say it.
- 真的吗?  -当然
- Really? -Totally.
掠夺者?
The Ravagers?
这是一个转移拉响警报，封锁大楼
It's a diversion. Sound the alarms, lock down the building.
闪光
The flashy flash.
你总是知道如何带来乐趣
You always know how to bring the fun.
等一下，我需要补充水分
Hold on, I need to hydrate.
-我们得走了-你要去哪里?回来了
-We have to go. -Where are you going? Come back.
你疯了吗?欢乐时光刚刚开始
Are you crazy? Happy hour just started.
它……它不能
It... It cannot be.
我的儿子，特查拉，瓦坎达的王储
My son, T'Challa, Crown Prince of Wakanda,
被外星人从地球绑架
was abducted from Earth by an alien spacecraft.
如果你有任何关于他的下落的信息，
If you have any information regarding his whereabouts,
我们要求你对这个归航信标作出 的响应
we ask that you respond to this homing beacon.
——特查拉…… 爸爸
-And T'Challa... -Baba.
…如果你在那里，
...if you are out there,
你是一个明亮的燃烧的光 在数十亿的夜空，
you're one bright burning light in the night sky of billions,
，我们将搜索每一个 ，直到我们找到你
and we will search every last one of them until we find you
在这个平面上或下一个平面上
on this plane or the next.
恰恰，我希望你能理解，
Oh, Cha-Cha, I hope you can understand,
我欠了收税员一笔债而你就是我的还款单
I had a debt with the Collector and you were the payment.
特查拉，现在是你大逃亡的时候了
Oh, T'Challa, now it's time for one of your great escapes.
你没事吧,孩子?
You okay, kid?
你骗了我!
You lied to me!
我是在保护你
I was protecting you.
我们是在说任务吗?还是说这是“家庭琐事”?
Are we talking about the mission? Or is this "family stuff"?
你告诉我我的家园被摧毁了
You told me my homeland had been destroyed.
我的家人被杀害
My family killed.
这怎么能保护我?
How is that protecting me?
哇可能是家里的事吧
Whoa. Guess it's family stuff.
有时候，你需要听到谎言才能看到真相
Sometimes you need to hear a lie to see the truth.
你跟我一样，特查拉
You're just like me, T'Challa.
我一点也不像你
I am nothing like you.
你是个探险家，星爵
You're an explorer, Star-Lord.
对于像你这样的人，像我们这样的人，过去只是一座监狱
And for people like you, like us, the past ain't nothing but a prison.
你不应该跟他们一起下去
You don't belong down there with them.
你属于这里，和你的家人在一起
You belong up here with us, with your family.
你不是我的家人
You are not my family.
你永远不会是
You never were.
该死的,这很伤我的心
Damn, that hurts.
收藏家已经准备好了
The Collector is ready for you.
我得为刚才和星云的尴尬道歉
I must apologize for all that awkwardness back there with Nebula.
我就是讨厌戏剧
I simply abhor drama.
你的着装却不一样
Your outfit would suggest otherwise.
你找我做什么，提文?
What is it you want with me, Tivan?
小卖部里有一堵空白的墙
There is a blank wall in the commissary
我只是还没找到合适的部分
that I just haven't been able to find the right piece for.
我只是一个普通人，算不上一件艺术品
I am just an ordinary human, hardly a work of art.
啊我必须承认，我现在看到了你本人，你是
Ah. I must admit now that I see you in the flesh, you are.
你确定你不会飞也不会用眼睛发射激光之类的吗?
Are you sure you can't fly or shoot lasers out of your eyes or something?
我们去打几轮，你就知道了
Let's go a few rounds and you can find out.
通过我更喜欢你在笼子里
Pass. I prefer you in the cage.
在我的家乡，
Where I come from,
历史从来不会善待那些把人关在笼子里的人
history has never looked kindly on those who lock men in cages.
记下来
Maw, make a note.
看来他确实有超能力
It appears he does have a super power after all.
他可以只用装模作样就把人烦死
He can bore someone to death using only his sanctimony.
我们别浪费墙的空间了
Let's not waste the wall space.
解剖他，把他的尸体撕成碎片
Dissect him and strip his remains for parts.
我的女儿
Daughter of mine.
你怎么能这样对我们?
How could you do this to us?
敬我最好的朋友，特查拉你是最差的
To my best friend, T'Challa. You are the worst.
但话又说回来，每个故事都有两面性
But then again, there are two sides to every story.
放松,新人我是来救你的
Relax, new guy. I'm here to rescue you.
我可不喜欢你改变主意
Not like you to change your mind.
哦,我没有这一直是我们的计划
Oh, I didn't. This was always the plan.
我告诉特查拉收集器 从一开始就在追他
I told T'Challa that the Collector was after him right from the jump.
这是什么工作?-更像是一个诡计
-What is this job? -More of a ruse.
你看，我欠了收税员一笔债
You see, I have this debt with the Collector
他是来收钱的
and, well, he's come to collect.
-他想要什么?-一句话，你，恰恰
-And what does he want? -In a word, you, Cha-Cha.
我不知道那艘瓦坎达船
I had no idea about that Wakandan ship.
我只知道我们有机会和收税员结清债务，
All I knew was that we had an opening to settle my debt with the Collector,
从他手下偷走了余烬
and steal the Embers right out from under him.
什么?星爵
What? Classic Star-Lord.
不让你知道是特查拉的主意
Hey, it was T'Challa's idea to keep you in the dark.
因为他知道我不会让他掉进陷阱的
'Cause he knew I would never let him walk into a trap.
看看我们的结局
Look where we ended up.
所有分心,
All a distraction,
给我提供了必要的掩护来获取这个，创世纪的余烬
providing me the necessary cover to obtain this, the Embers of Genesis.
热的你们真棒
Hot damn. You guys are good.
- T 'Challa呢?别担心
-What about T'Challa? - Not to worry.
他把他的逃跑计划藏在心里
He's keeping his escape plan close to his chest.
收藏家:不，不是那样，Carina
THE COLLECTOR: No, not like that, Carina.
即使以奴隶的标准来看，你们也是愚蠢的
Even by a slave standard, you are foolish.
我喜欢你说的不要把人关在笼子里
I liked that thing you said about not locking people in cages.
谢谢你！我永远感激你
Thank you. I am forever in your debt.
囚犯已经 逃跑了所有单位到第七区，警戒>
The prisoners have escaped. All units to sector seven.
什么样的人会不辞而别地离开派对?
What kind of being leaves a party without saying goodbye?
直觉告诉我这种事在你身上经常发生
Something tells me this happens to you a lot.
很有冲击力，不是吗?
Packs quite a wallop, does it not?
我从一个喋喋不休的克朗人的尸体上砍下来的
I hacked it off the carcass of a terribly chatty Kronan.
当然，如果这不是你的风格，
Of course, if that's not your style,
我们还有很多可以玩的观察
there's plenty more we can play with. Observe.
一把用黑暗精灵统治者手中的暗物质锻造的匕首
A dagger forged in dark matter taken from the ruler of the Dark Elves.
或者你更喜欢更优雅的东西?
Or perhaps you prefer something a touch more elegant?
哦那个女人很有品味!
Oh. That woman had taste!
一把死亡剑，由阿斯加德死亡女神赠予
A necrosword, courtesy of the Asgardian Goddess of Death.
-啊
-Whoa.
跑!我们运行
- Run! -We were running.
好吧，我们跑快点
Okay, we'll run faster.
-到船上去是你疯了吗?
-Get to the ship. -Are you crazy?
-你自己是不会吃的不是疯了……
-You'll never take them yourself. -Not crazy...
疯了
Mad.
一个遗憾
A pity.
你抛弃了你的家和家人
You abandoned your home and family,
现在，你的新家庭抛弃了你业力
and now, your new family has abandoned you. Karma.
也许你没听说过，劫掠者从不单飞
Maybe you haven't heard, a Ravager never flies solo.
Yondu,甜!现在它是一个派对
Yondu, sweet! Now it's a party.
我绝不可能不带着孩子就离开这里
Ain't no way in hell I was going to leave here without my kid.
吃这个
Eat this.
我们走吧打它!
Let's go. Punch it!
-勇度和特查拉呢?-我肯定他们做得很好
-What about Yondu and T'Challa? -I'm sure they're doing fine.
-好的,任何想法?黏糊糊的手指
-Okay, any ideas? -Sticky fingers.
可以工作
Could work.
——的胶水吗?-你
-Who's the glue? -You are.
-因为你骗了我公平点
-Because you lied to me. -Fair point.
勇度:就这些吗?
Is that all you got?
你觉得这能控制我吗?
You think this can contain me?
可爱无论你去哪里，躲多远，
Cute. No matter where you go or how far you hide,
这个星系里没有一个角落是我无法掌控的
there is not a corner in this galaxy beyond my grasp.
当然,当然无论什么很酷的故事
Sure, sure. Whatever. Cool story.
我相信你知道该怎么做
I trust you'll know what to do with this.
哦，我有一些想法
Oh, I have some ideas.
Carina，能把手镯给我了吗?
Carina, can I have my bracelet now?
没有触摸,船底座不!
No touching, Carina. No!
不，不，不留下来停!
No, no, no, no. Stay. Stop!
停下来思考我照顾了你们所有人我让你们有地方住
Stop and think. I took care of all of you. I put a roof over your heads.
哦业力
Oh. Karma.
勇度:我们不可能步行出去
We're never getting out on foot.
然后我们将飞向天空
Then we'll take to the skies.
所有机组人员到场 ，并有奇迹发生
All crew members present and accounted for by some miracle.
那我们在会合点见
Then I will see you at the rendezvous point.
复制,恰恰舞
Copy that, Cha-Cha.
看来有个偷渡者
Looks like we've got a stowaway.
你对离家出走的人一直很有好感
You always did have a soft spot for runaways.
-听着，特查拉，我只想说-没必要
-Look, T'Challa, I just wanted to say-- -There's no need.
是我告诉你我想去看看这个世界的
I was the one who told you I wanted to see the world.
你只是让我看到了宇宙
All you did was show me the universe.
哦,是的她真是个美人，不是吗?
Oh, yeah. She really is a beaut, isn't she?
我一直觉得在这里像在家里一样
I've always felt at home up here.
但现在，我知道了一切，我不太确定我属于哪里
But now, knowing everything, I'm not quite sure where I belong.
我小时候见过很多太空旅行者，孩子
Seen a lot of space travelers in my day, kid.
如果说我从你身上学到了什么，
And if I've learned anything from watching you,
在任何星球上，在任何人群中，
on any planet, among any people,
这个星系里没有一个地方不属于你
there ain't no place in this galaxy where you don't belong.
你想去哪里，这才是问题所在，不是吗?
Where you want to be, that's the question, isn't it?
星爵先生，在这个问题上，你得听从自己的内心
You're just gonna have to follow your heart on that one, Mr. Star-Lord.
爸爸 -(颤抖的声音)我的儿子，我的儿子
-Baba. -(VOICE SHAKING) My son, my son.
我就知道你会找到回家的路
I knew you would find your way home to us.
很抱歉我花了这么长时间
I'm sorry it took me so long.
让我把你介绍给我的家人
Let me introduce you to the family I made along the way.
你一定是特查拉的父亲
Uh, you must be T'Challa's father.
很高兴见到你，先生，你儿子是银河英雄
Uh, pleased to meet you, sir. Your son is a galactic hero.
我的朋友，这听起来很像种族灭绝
My friend, that sounds an awful lot like genocide.
-不,不,不因为它是随机的-嗯
-No, no, no. Because it's random. -Uh-huh.
我还要补充一点，高效
And I might add, efficient.
爸爸!
Dad!
我是说，如果你真想给它贴上标签，
I mean, if you really wanted to put a label on it,
特查拉和我是最好的朋友
T'Challa and I are best friends.
是啊，跳点是最好的
Oh, yeah, jump points are the best.
它们让你的脸乱糟糟的，但它们很有趣
They make your face all scrambly, but they're a lot of fun.
我还在想我儿子怎么会在你的飞船里
I am still wondering how exactly my son came to be in your spaceship.
有趣的故事，殿下你看，我接受了这份工作——
Funny story, Your Highness. You see, I took this job--
我迷路了，爸爸勇度找到了我
I was lost, Baba. Yondu found me.
从一个家庭团聚 到另一个…
And from one family reunion to another...
我看见你的眼睛了
I saw your eyes
而你让我笑了
And you made me smile
呃,抱歉我们关闭
Uh, sorry. We're closed.
什么吗,彼得?就不能抽出点时间陪陪亲爱的老爸吗?
What, Peter? Can't spare a little time for dear old Dad?
太糟糕了，可能会拼写 the end of the world.
Too bad this might spell the end of the world.
但那是另一天的故事了
But that's a story for another day.
我爱上你了
I was falling in love